这好像很容易
Well, that's easy.
好的  接下来我们做什么
All right. What do we do next?
建立你的档案
Set up your profile.
姓名  玛莎·罗杰斯
Name--Martha Rodgers.
性别  女  好的
Sex--female. Right.
-民族  -色盲
- Race-- - Color-blind.
为什么我非得归到某类里面
Why should I categorize myself?
填灰色不明  亲爱的
Shades of gray, darling.
-年龄  -长生不老
- Age? - Ageless.
不  青春永驻更好
No, better yet timeless.
你不会真想这么填吧
Oh, you don't want to put that.
那听起来你像是博物馆里的展品
It makes you sound like you belong in a museum.
你说得有道理
Oh, you have a point.
我知道了  就填"足够大"好了
Uh... I know. Type in "old enough."
这个好
Nice. Uh-huh.
你们在搞什么
What are you ladies doing?
阿丽克西斯缠着让我弄个Myface账户
Alexis is assisting me in creating a my face account.
-我想你意思是  -先让我说
- I think you mean  - Save your breath.
我一早上都在纠正她
I've been correcting her all morning.
这是我自己的  对不对
Well, it's my face, isn't it?
不是你的或其他人的  我不
It's not your face or someone else's face. I don't--
不管怎样  我们剧组的成员
Well, anyway, my fellow cast members
总说吹嘘这网站有多有趣
Have been raving about what fun it is,
是强大的人际关系网工具  所以我也加了
What a great networking tool it is, so here I am.
现在你只需要选一张照片
And now you just need to select a photo
-显示在你个人主页上  -好的  是选
- For your profile page.- Okay, should we go
梦幻版呢
Dramatic...or
广告版
Commercial...or
还是性感版呢
Sassy? Mm.
你就没有新世纪的照片吗
Don't you have anything from this century?
怎么了  你觉得这发型过时了吗
Why, you think the hair's a bit dated?
不仅仅因为发型
Not exactly what I was getting at.
我知道你想说什么
I know what you were getting at.
你也不再是小年轻了  知道吗
You're no spring chicken yourself, you know?
最近你照过镜子没有
Have you looked in the mirror lately?
两个词形容你恰当不过  "抬头纹"  "色衰"
I have two words for you-- "hairline" and "receding."
还是先打点好自己吧
Ha! Made you look.
她骗到你了  爸爸
She totally got you, dad.
是的  贝克特  是有命案了
Yes, Beckett. Either there's a dead body
还是你想念我迷人的声音
Or you just want to hear my sultry voice.
有命案是吧  哪里
Dead body it is. Where?
你动作还真快  卡塞尔
You got here fast, Castle.
-城这边可是我的地盘  -什么情况
- My side of town. - So what do we got?
能让我来吗
May I?
-请便  -谢谢
- Be my guest.- Thank you.
-受害人叫卡勒布·谢密斯基  -谢曼斯基
- Our victim's name is Caleb Shiminsky. - Shimansky.
-那是"曼"  -是"曼"
- Is that an "a"? - Yeah, it's an "a."
他像凯文·贝肯在《银色快手》那样送货
He was pulling a Kevin Bacon in "Quicksilver," when all
-抱歉  什么  -《银色快手》
- I'm sorry, a what? - "Quicksilver."
凯文·贝肯演的是自行车快递员
Kevin Bacon is a bike messenger who failed as
埃斯波西托  让他开开眼
Esposito, take him to school.
受害人是卡勒布·谢曼斯基  自行车快递员
The victim is Caleb Shimansky, an on-duty bike messenger.
嫌犯带面罩  开四门轿车
A masked suspect in a black 4-door plows into him,
撞了他  他当场死亡
Killing him instantly.
然后嫌犯偷走了他的包裹
Then the suspect steals the messenger bag,
跳上车  一溜烟跑了
Jumps in his ride and jets off.
看到没  没那么复杂
See? That wasn't so hard.
不  不  是不错
No, no. It's good
如果你喜欢无聊非畅销作家版本的话
If you like the dull, non-bestseller version.
我觉得我讲得无懈可击
I thought I gave it some flair.
我猜应该有很多证人
I'm assuming we have plenty of witnesses.
不少  有3人记下了嫌犯的车牌号
Several. Three of them got the suspect's license plate number.
这就像是戳穿了骗子的把戏
Aw, man. It's like having a cheat code.
有多个证人和车牌号
You've got multiple witnesses and a license plate number?
这你5分钟就能搞定了
It's gonna take you all of, what, five minutes to solve it?
查过嫌犯的车牌
Ran the suspect's plates.
一小时前那辆车报失了
The car was reported stolen an hour ago.
戴面罩还开偷来的车  精心策划
Masked man in a stolen car, our thief planned this
显然他想要的是那个包裹
And obviously wanted what was ever in that messenger bag.
那包被害人要送的东西  包裹或是纸盒
Something our vic was delivering-- A package or a box.
马上联系快递公司
Contact the courier company.
我想知道那包里有什么
I want to know what was in that bag.
不管是什么
Whatever it was,
都重要到需要杀死快递员
It was important enough to kill the messenger.
长官  我们已经全面通缉那辆车
Sir, we got an A.P.B. Out on the car,
但埃斯波西托和莱恩还没什么发现
But Esposito and Ryan got nothing on the canvass.
知道包裹里是什么了吗
Do we know what was in the package?
快递公司正在查
The, uh, courier company's looking into it right now.
不管是什么  某人认为为那东西值得杀人
Whatever it was, somebody thought that it was worth killing for.
我现在能想到的
Off the top of my head,
只有核弹发射的密码
I'm gonna with nuclear launch codes,
迪克·切尼[美国副总统]正走向邪恶的道路
Dick Cheney's soul on its way to the devil--
想法不错  卡塞尔  非常不错
All good theories, Castle. All good theories.
长官  你没事吧
Um, sir... Are you okay?
你看上去有点走神
You seem a little distracted.
没有  我正在想
No, I'm focused...
我的管辖区正在接受检查
Focused on my precinct being up for review
我们的破案率现在低于
And our case closure rate being just under One-P-p's
新管理政策要求的最小值
New mandated minimum, which, of course,
当然  还没有包括预算减少的问题
Doesn't take the budget cuts into consideration.
我究竟怎么才能用更少的探员
Now how the hell am I supposed to catch more bad guys
抓更多的罪犯
With fewer detectives?
头儿  快递公司说
Yo, Cap. Courier company said the vic
死者出事时身上只有一个包裹
Only had one package in his bag,
发件人住在西2区27-39  3C座
Picked up from 27-39 West 2nd, apartment, 3-c.
发件人叫夏·尼达尔·麦塔  我查过了
Sent by one S. Nidal Mattar. I ran it through the system.
恐怖分子名单中有夏奇拉·尼达尔·麦塔
There's a Shakir Nidal Mattar on the terror watch list.
-也许是同一个人  -包裹是要送到哪里的
- Could be the same guy. - Where was the package going?
-东72区 6-1-4  -东72区  那是64区管片
- 6-1-4 East 72nd. - East 72nd? That's the 64th precinct.
长官  可能是恐怖袭击
Sir, that could be an attack.
全线警备  所有人撤离
I need a full tactical alert. Have 'em evacuate the building.
我向国土安全部汇报
I'll coordinate with Homeland Security.
我是贝克特探长
This is Detective Beckett.
可能有恐怖袭击  目标64
We have a possible terrorist attack against the 64...
我是罗伊·蒙哥马利上尉
Yeah, this is Captain Roy Montgomery...
让紧急服务小组立即查地址  明白吗
Get E.S.U. over to the pickup address immediately. You got it.
所有单位警戒
All units on alert.
我是12区负责人蒙哥马利
Yeah, this is Montgomery over at 12th precinct.
纽约警察  举起手里  安全
NYPD! NYPD! Hands! Clear!
尼达尔·麦塔在哪里
Where's Nidal Mattar?
夏奇拉·尼达尔·麦塔  他在哪里
Shakir Nidal Mattar-- Where is he?
这里没有什么夏奇拉·尼达尔·麦塔
There's no Shakir Nidal Mattar here.
只有萨利·尼德梅尔
Only Sally Niedermeyer.
太太  今早你是不是找快递公司送了包裹
Ma'am, did you send a package by bike courier this morning?
没错  是我
Yes, I did.
夏·尼达尔·麦塔  是萨·尼德梅尔
S. Nidal Mattar? S. Niedermeyer.
肯定是快递写错了名字
Some bozo at the courier company wrote the name wrong.
我们搞错了
Our bad.
我会  我们会  把门修好的
I'm going to--we can-- Yeah, we can fix this.
很抱歉
Sorry.
尼德梅尔太太  有人偷了你的包裹
Mrs. Niedermeyer, somebody stole the courier bag
你的包裹和一起刑事案件有关
That your package was in, and in the course of the crime,
自行车快递员被杀害了
A bike messenger was killed.
太可怕了
Oh, that's terrible.
我们正在查为何包裹被偷
Yeah, we're trying to figure out why they stole the bag.
-收件人是64区  是吗  -没错
- You sent it to the 64th Precinct, is that right? - Yes.
-能说说包裹里是什么吗  -不能
- Could you tell us what was in the package?- No.
-不能吗  -不能
- No? - No.
是你不想说  还是不记得
"No" you don't want to or "no" you don't remember
-还是你也不知道里面是什么  -是的
- Or know what's in the package? - Yes...
后半句的意思  也不知道里面是什么那句
To the second part, the--the--the don't know part.
这个包裹是哪来的
Where'd you get the package?
我最疼爱的侄子布莱迪给我的
From my favorite nephew-- Brady.
好的  怎么能找到布莱迪呢
Okay, where can we find Brady?
-监狱里  -真的监狱吗
- In prison. - "Prison" prison?
他什么时候给你包裹的
When did he give you the package?
10年前
Ten years ago,
就在他被关进去之前
Just before they sent him upstate.
布莱迪来找我  给了我这个包裹
Brady came over, handed me the package,
跟我说 "姑妈  收好这个包裹
And then he said,"mema, take good care of this package.
跟谁都不要说
"Don't tell anyone about it.
也绝对不要打开它"
And never, ever open it."
那你为什么突然要寄出去
Then why all of a sudden would you messenger it?
今早大约7点半  布莱迪给我打电话
Brady called... About 7:30 this morning,
让我立刻把它寄给
And asked me to send it right away
那个地址上的那个男的
To the man it was addressed to,
那个10年前逮捕他的人
The man who arrested him ten years ago--
罗伊·蒙哥马利探员
Detective Roy Montgomery.
现在是罗伊·蒙哥马利上尉了
It's Captain Roy Montgomery now.
看来你认识他
Oh. You know him?
是的  他是我们头儿
Yeah. He's our boss.
-包裹是寄给我的吗  -是的
- The package was coming to me?- Yeah.
-那人叫什么  -布莱迪·汤姆逊
- What's his name again?- Brady Thompson.
那时你在6-4区当探员
It was back when you were a Detective with the 6-4.
是的  我有点印象了
Oh, yeah. It's ringing some bells.
但他为何要寄个十年前的包裹给我
But why would he send me a 10yearold package?
埃斯波西托正在查
Esposito's on the phone with corrections.
他正准备去问问情况
He's trying to get an interview.
你有没有想起跟他有关的任何事情
Do you recall anything at all about him?
他入室抢劫被发现  杀害了一个女人
Yeah, he killed a lady-- a push-in robbery gone bad.
没有任何疑点的案子
Open-and-shut case.
我记得他供认不讳
I think we even got a confession out of him.
他姑妈说他一再强调
The aunt said that he was pretty insistent
要把这个包裹直接交到你手上
About getting the package directly to you.
你知道他为什么这么做吗
Do you know why that would be?
你可以去问问他
You would have to ask him.
除非你能通灵  他已经死了
Not unless you're performing a séance. He's dead.
今天上午在监狱里被人捅死了
Got shanked in prison this morning.
今天上午吗  绝非巧合
This morning? That's no coincidence.
把旧案子的资料全调出来
Have records pull everything from the old case.
如果我没记错  布莱迪那时已经结婚了
If memory serves, Brady was married when he went away.
查查他离婚没有  看看她知道些什么
See if the wife is still the wife and if she knows anything.
贝克特  打给监狱长
Beckett, call the Warden.
我要了解布莱迪被杀时的情况
I want to see what they know about Brady's murder.
还有他电话记录的复印件
And I need copies of all his phone calls.
我要知道他跟萨利姑妈说了什么
I want to know exactly what he said to Aunt Sally
-和跟任何人的通话记录  -好的
- And anyone else, for that matter. - Okay.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett.
佩斯利·谢曼斯基要见你
Paisley Shimansky's here to see you.
是自行车快递员的姐姐  失陪一下
That's the bike messenger's sister. Excuse me.
她怎么能办得到
How does she do that?
她比任何人都适合去谈
Better than anyone I know.
你没事吧
You okay?
她弟弟遇害  只因给我送快递
Her brother died trying to get something to me.
不  我不会善罢甘休
No, I'm not okay.
《灵书妙探》
第二季  第八集
监狱送过来布莱迪最后的两个电话记录
The prison sent over The last two phone calls Brady made.
我不能直接用平信寄过去吗
Can't I just put it in the mail?
不行  萨利姑妈  你必须亲自送过去
No, Aunt Sally. You've gotta take it down there yourself.
我的髋骨老毛病又发作了
Oh, my hip's been acting up again.
那就叫快递公司
Then call a messenger service.
-回头我给你钱  好吗  -好的
- I'll pay you back, okay? - All right.
好的  我会处理好的
Alright.  I'll take care of it.
我得挂了
I've gotta go now, okay?
照顾好自己  布莱迪  爱你
Take care now, Brady. Love you.
我也爱你  姑妈  我得挂了
Love you, too, mema. I-I gotta go.
包裹里的东西  一句也没提到
Nothing about what was in the package.
7点23分  他给妻子打了电话
At 7:23, he makes this phone call to his wife.
是的  我会付那些钱
Yes, I'll accept the charges.
-薇尔  -宝贝
- Val. - Hey, babe.
薇尔  听我说
Val, listen to me
记得上次你来看我时  说的话吗
Remember what we talked about last time you visited?
-我记得  -就是今天了
- I remember.- It's goin' down today.
你和杰瑞德现在就搬出那栋房子
You and Jared get out of the house now.
-但是  布莱迪  -没时间细说了  快走
- But, Brady-- - There's no time to talk. Just go
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be all right.
替我亲亲杰瑞德  好吗
Give Jared a kiss from dad, okay?
-我爱你  -我也爱你  拜
- I love you. - I love you, too. Bye.
布莱迪打完电话45分钟后  就被杀了
Brady was killed 45 minutes after those 2 phone calls.
但不知道他何被杀  凶手是谁
Yeah, but we don't have a why or a who.
还有这和神秘包裹有什么关系
Or a how it's related to your mystery package.
-监狱长有嫌犯吗  -监狱的院内都是人
- Warden have any suspects? - A whole prison yard full.
他在院内被杀  没目击者
He was shanked in the yard. There were no witnesses.
监狱长说抓到罪犯的可能性很渺茫
Warden's less than optimistic about catching the killer.
布莱迪常惹麻烦吗
Brady have any beefs?
他是个模范犯人
Apparently he was the model prisoner.
那就是外面雇人干的
Then it must have been a hit, ordered from the outside.
和杀死快递员的是同一个
By the same guy who killed our messenger.
联系到布莱迪的妻子了吗
Any luck on tracking down Brady's wife?
没那么走运  他们走得很迅速
Big fat zippo. But they left the apartment in a hurry.
我追踪他们的手机  信用卡记录
I pinged their cell phones, tracked their credit cards.
-她躲起来了  -也不是完全消失
- She's off the grid. - Maybe not completely.
我打电话去她儿子的学校
I just got off the phone with the son's school.
据校长说
According to the principal,
布莱迪儿子每周二都不去上课
Brady's kid misses class every Tuesday
因为患有严重的呼吸系统疾病
Because he's got some kind of respiratory condition.
明天就是周二  查到医生的名字了吗
Tomorrow's Tuesday. You get the doctor's name?
明天一早我们去办公室守着
Let's set up on the office in the morning.
也许能有收获
We might get lucky.
妈妈  你在干什么
Whatcha doing, mother,
在研究你的剧本吗
Working on your play?
我倒希望
Oh, I wish.
想加我为好友的人都快挤爆了
I've been bombarded with friend requests.
这简直像在兼职工作
It's like a part-time job.
有些人实在太可笑了
And these exchanges are just ridiculous.
多特·埃里森
Dot Ellison,
是我死都不想再联系的人
Who I have absolutely no desire to reconnect with,
刚刚却浪费了我20分钟的生命
Has just wasted 20 minutes of my life
一直跟我讲
Recounting the bravery
她的猫是多么勇敢地面对肾结石
Of her cat passing a kidney stone.
这样算不错了
Well, it could've been worse.
她没给寄视频算你走运了
She could've sent you a video.
赶时髦这做法真是失策
Joining up with this fad was a terrible mistake.
网络上就没带给人什么好东西
Nothing good comes from the Internet.
你又收到一个好友邀请
Oh, you just got another friend request.
天啊  是查特·帕拉本
O.M.G.! Chet Palaburn.
谁是查特·帕拉本
Who's Chet Palaburn?
明星运动员  班长  返校舞会王子
Star athlete, class president, homecoming king...
我高中时的爱人  也是我的初恋
My high school sweetheart, and my first.
后面那句真不用告诉我的
I really didn't need to know that last part.
他的请求还附加了条消息
Oh, oh. He sent a message with his request.
"我现住纽约  很想见你
"I'm living in New York now and would love to see you.
玛莎  你一点都没变"
Martha, you haven't changed a bit."
查特·帕拉本  你能相信吗
Oh, Chet Palaburn. Can you believe it?
看到那条消息没
And did you see that message?
你知道查特的留言
You do know that Chet's comments
是基于你20岁时的照片
Are based on a 20-year-old photo?
我该接受请求  加他为好友吗
Should I accept his friend request?
我上次见他的时候
I mean, the last time I laid eyes on him,
我才18  现在他又看到了这照片
I was 18 and--and now he sees this photo
但是我现在是
And now this and--ugh.
-我该怎么办  -你得自己决定
- What do I do? - It's your call.
网上总有像多特和猫咪历险记的故事
There's always Dot and her kitty cat's medical mysteries.
你还好吧
Everything okay?
快递员的案子线索又断了
Another dead end in the messenger case.
警察找到了撞他的车
Uniforms located the stolen car that ran him down,
但鉴证科一无所获  无指纹  无头发
But C.S.U. got bubkes-- no prints, no hairs.
听着越来越像专业人士干的
It's sounding more and more like a professional hit.
监控状况如何
What about surveillance?
弃车地点附近有摄像头吗
Any cameras around where the car was dumped?
没  这蒙面男很懂行
Nah. Our masked man knew what he was doing.
至少医生这条线有所收获
Well, at least our tip on the doctor paid off.
被害人的妻子  今早带着儿子去看医生了
Prison vic's wife came in with her son first thing this morning.
头儿和贝克特正在找她问话
The Captain and Beckett are interviewing her now.
-我要去  -我不会
- I'm gonna go... - I wouldn't do...
你们知道有谁可能害死他吗
Do you have any idea who killed him?
我们正在调查
We're working on it.
汤姆逊夫人  你知不知道
Mrs. Thompson, do you know anything about a package
你丈夫昨天让他姨妈萨利
That your husband asked his Aunt Sally
-替他寄个包裹  -知道
- To send out for him yesterday? - Yeah.
那是他的保险单
It was his insurance policy.
他临走前交给她的
He gave it to her when he went away.
-保险单  -那是证据
- Insurance policy?  - It was proof
他虽然因杀人入狱  却并没犯案
He didn't kill the woman he went to jail for murdering.
-但他当初认罪了  -他或许是认罪了
- But he confessed. - Well, he might have confessed,
但其实并未犯罪
But he didn't do it.
汤姆逊夫人 恕我直言
With all due respect, Mrs. Thompson,
一半的囚犯都会指天画地地发誓
Half the men in prison will swear up and down
说自己没犯罪
They didn't do it.
那他们的妻子都会每个月
Do those men's wives get a package
收到一份内有七千现金的信封吗
In the mail every month with $7,000 cash in it?
你丈夫是为了钱
Uh, your husband confessed
才认下了自己不曾犯有的罪
To a murder he didn't commit for money?
我知道这听上去不可信
I know this will sound crazy,
但我们别无他法
But we didn't know what else to do.
杰瑞德出生时便患有罕见的呼吸疾病
Jared was born with a rare respiratory disease,
我们没钱  也没有医保
And we didn't have the money or the insurance
让他接受相应的治疗
To get him the therapy he needed.
要是布莱迪当时没那么干
If Brady hadn't done what he did,
杰瑞德现在根本不可能活着
Jared wouldn't even be alive right now.
布莱迪是否告诉过你
Did Brady ever tell you who actually
他在帮谁顶罪吗
Committed the murder He went away for?
没有  我怀疑他自己也不知道实情
No. I don't even know if he knew who it was.
这十年来  你从没问过是谁联络他
Over ten years, you never asked who his contact was,
是谁接洽他  是谁付你钱吗
Who approached him, who was paying you?
你只是装作什么都不知道  收钱就好
You just conveniently never bothered to ask?
我问过  但布莱迪认为
I asked! But Brady felt that
我知道得越少就越安全
The less I knew, the safer I would be.
连那个包裹都没写回邮地址
Even the packages didn't have a return address.
上尉  我丈夫刚刚遇害
Look, Captain, my husband was just killed.
我已经知无不言
I'm telling you all I know.
好吧  我们目前所掌握的
Okay, so what we know so far
就是大约四个月前
Is that about four months ago,
给布莱迪的酬劳开始迟到
The payments to Brady started arriving late,
减少  甚至最后  停寄了
Short and then finally, not at all.
据他妻子所言  因此布莱迪决定
And according to the wife, that's when Brady decided
寄出他的保险单
To messenger over his insurance policy.
来证明自己的清白
That was supposed to prove his innocence.
不管是谁付钱给他
Our patsy Brady had to be in communication
布莱迪肯定一直在跟他联系
With whoever was making payments.
监狱应该有布莱迪会客谈话的记录
Prison should have a record of everyone Brady talked to.
我们查过电话记录了  一无所获
We already checked his phone logs. There's nothing there.
-电邮呢  -马上去查
- How about email? - We're running it down.
不管布莱迪说过什么  反正奏效了
Well, whatever Brady said, it worked.
他的酬劳又按时送达  直到一个月前  又停了
Payments started up again, then a month ago, nothing.
没准布莱迪受够了这情况
Think maybe Brady got fed up with the situation?
他想反正对方
Figured if whoever he made the deal with
自己都没遵守  那他也不必坚持了
Wasn't holding up their end of the bargain, why was he?
然后他联系了他姨妈萨利
Then he calls up his Aunt Sally,
叫她把能证明自己清白的证据
Asks her to send the evidence that proves his innocence
寄给负责逮捕他的警官
To the arresting officer.
有没可能有人在监听他的电话
Is it possible someone was monitoring his calls?
不管是谁杀了快递员
I mean, whoever killed our bike messenger
肯定是收到了包裹寄出的消息
Had to have been tipped off the package was in motion.
唯一能监听电话的  就是监狱工作人员
The only people that monitor calls are prison staff.
十年来  每月七千美金  那可就是百万美金
$7,000 a month for 10 years is almost $1 million total.
不管我们在查的是谁  很显然
Whoever we're dealing with obviously has the means
他有的是收买人的办法
To buy somebody off.
查一下监狱的轮值表
Get the duty roster from the prison.
看布莱迪打电话时是谁当值
See who was working when Brady made his calls.
为他老婆孩子办好证人保护计划
Set up a protection detail for the wife and the kid.
已经办好了  长官
It's already done, sir.
上尉  你有认罪口供和证据
Captain, you had the confessions, the evidence.
每个人都会做出相同的决定
Anyone would've come to the same conclusion.
我不够努力  还以为可以结案了
I didn't push hard enough.  I knew this case was off.
每件事情都这么有条不紊
Everything just fell into place so perfectly.
看看现在什么情况
Now what have we got?
和凶手毫无关联的人无辜被害
An innocent bystander with no connection to the killer.
而且根本没有物证
And without physical evidence,
根本无法确定谁开的那辆车
There's no way of tracking who was driving that car.
想从狱中凶犯那找到突破口
And catching a break on a prison murder?
可没那么容易
That's a long shot,
尤其这事还牵涉到腐败案
Especially if you're dealing with a corrupt guard.
但我们手中还有十年前那桩杀人案
But we still have the original murder from ten years ago.
一切事情从那里开始
Everything started there.
刚出了两桩凶杀案  你却想去查
Two fresh bodies, and you want to look
十年前的老案子
At a murder 10years cold?
就拿我写小说来说
Uh... When I'm writing a story,
万事总是开头难
The beginning is always the hardest,
但只要起了个好头
But if you nail that,
其他的自然就不在话下了
The rest of it could just fall into place.
卡塞尔  这不是你的小说
Castle, this is not one of your books.
但这是个谜  所有的谜案都是一样的
No, but it is a mystery, and all mysteries are the same--
动机  机会  掩饰  良知
Motive, opportunity, cover-up, conscience.
今天的两起命案  是为了掩盖十年前的案子
These murders today were to cover up one ten years ago.
那线索就该从那查起
That's where your leads are gonna be.
上尉  你觉得呢
Come on, Captain. What do you say?
咱们就来小小缅怀下往事吧
Let's take a little trip down memory lane.
奥利维亚·德比西  20岁
Olivia Debiasse, 20 years old.
邻居发现她陈尸自家公寓
Neighbors found her bludgeoned to death in her apartment.
她公寓肯定少了什么
Hmm. There were some things missing from her apartment.
不论是谁杀了她
Whoever killed her
都想让这看起来是一起抢劫案
Tried to make it look like a robbery gone wrong.
我们调查的那位勤杂工
There should be something in there
肯定跟这事多少有点关系
About a handyman that we looked at for it.
他有案底  而且就在那楼里工作
He had a criminal record, he worked in the building.
是他干的话  我可真入错了行
If it was him, I'm in the wrong line of work.
勤杂工月收入7000块
$7,000 a month for a handyman?
有证据指向布莱迪后  就排除了他
We moved off him once we moved on Brady.
后来接到了个匿名线报
An anonymous tip came in.
那会来说还真够及时的
Felt like a break at the time.
我们抓了他  审了大概
Yeah, brought him in, leaned on him for, what,
估计最多半小时  他就招了
Maybe a half-hour before he broke.
知道吗  很有趣的是
You know, it's funny.
我从未真正看过这些报告
I-I never actually even looked at some of these reports
因为检调单位送来的时候
Because once the canvassing detectives turned them in,
布莱迪早就被羁押了
We already had Brady in custody.
上面说了 奥利维亚被害当晚
Well, it says here that Olivia went to a party earlier
-先去参加了派对  -是在皮尔逊俱乐部
- The night she was killed.- It says here the Pierson Club.
皮尔逊俱乐部
The Pierson Club?
那可是上流社会聚集地
That's high society.
那可是犯罪的温床
That's crime de la crime.
我的钱只够存银行  他们的钱足够买下银行
My money goes in banks. Their money buys banks.
长官  听听这个  一名女服务生说
Sir, listen to this. A waitress gave a statement
她看到奥利维亚在派对上和一名男子
Saying that she saw Olivia having a heated argument
发生了激烈争吵
With a man at the party.
-阴谋味浓了  -这里没提名字
- The plot thickens.  - Mmhmm. There's no name,
但根据她所描述的
But according to the description she gave,
他二十多岁  中等身材
He was in his mid20s, medium build,
身穿蓝色外衣  戴橙色条纹领带
Wearing a blue blazer and an orange striped tie.
我不知道你们怎么看
Ooh, I don't know about you guys.
我看就是个有钱的纨绔子弟在那泡妞
But I am getting a delicious millionaire playboy vibe here.
女服务生记得
The waitress was under the impression
他是跟奥利维亚一起来的
That he arrived with Olivia.
奥利维亚最好的朋友是她的同事
Olivia's best friend was a gal that she worked with.
也许她知道奥利维亚当时跟谁在一起
Maybe she could tell us who Olivia hung out with.
帕穆特刚重新看了
Perlmutter just finished reviewing
奥利维亚当时的尸检报告
Olivia's autopsy report from back in the day.
他说有所发现
He says he found something.
你们去停尸房
You guys take the morgue.
-我跟进奥利维亚的朋友这边  -谢谢  长官
- I'll follow-up on Olivia's friend. - Thank you, sir.
我重新看了看德比西女士的资料
I've gone through Ms. Debiasse's files,
她的尸检报告实在乏善可陈
And her autopsy was fairly limited.
我猜是因为布莱迪认罪了
I assume, when Brady confessed,
法医就觉得没必要太过仔细
The M.E. decided not to be thorough.
他漏了什么吗
Did he miss something?
-这很难说  -你直觉怎么认为
- It's hard to say. - What does your gut tell you?
我直觉认为  我现在很饿  但是
My gut tells me I'm hungry, but I'm not
在打发你们俩之前  我是吃不上东西的
Gonna be able to eat until I'm done with the two of you,
所以我就痛快告诉你们
So why don't I just tell you
我训练有素的法医技能告诉我
What my keen M.E. Training tells me?
布莱迪说他是用棒球棒袭击奥利维亚
All right, Brady said he hit Olivia with a baseball bat.
但看看这里  从这些伤口
But look at these. When I look at these wounds
和她颅骨骨折的情况来看
And the skull fracture pattern,
我认为这绝不是球棒所伤
I'm just not seeing a baseball bat strike.
布莱迪说谎说杀了人
Brady lied about killing her.
所以胡说行凶手法  也不稀奇
He might have lied about what was used to do it.
你能确定她是怎么死的吗
Can you determine how she was killed?
我只能凭推测
It'd only be speculating.
要证实的话  得给她头骨照X光才成
To do it properly, I'd have to x-ray the skull
还得检查她的遗骸
And examine the remains.
你想掘出她的遗体
You want to exhume the body?
这是唯一的办法
The only way to do it right.
再说  谁知道还能不能有其他发现
Plus, who knows what else I might find?
奥利维亚由母亲养大  母亲也已过世
Olivia was raised by a single mom who's deceased as well.
我找找她的亲戚  看能帮上什么
So let me call the next of kin and see what I can do.
抱歉
Excuse me.
你确定在这吃东西卫生吗
You sure it's sanitary to be eating here?
你知道我们这用什么消毒剂吗
You know the strength of the disinfectants we use here?
全市就数这房间最干净
This is the cleanest room in the city.
-我吃不下去  -爱心便当哦
- I couldn't.  - Homemade.
-我咽不下  -有进展了
- I couldn't. - Caught a break.
上尉找死者朋友谈过了
The Captain talked to the friend.
-她记得奥利维亚和谁一起吗  -杰夫·迪伦翰
- Does she remember who Olivia was with? - Jeff Dilahunt
法律咨询公司的合伙人
Who's had his fair share of run-ins with the law.
而且他的信托基金价值数百万美金
And he has a trust fund worth millions.
每月支付七千美金是绰绰有余
Enough to pay $7,000 a month.
-答对了  -太好了
- Bingo.  - Boo-yah.
我和奥利维亚是在夜店认识的
Uh, I met Olivia at a nightclub.
她来城里才不久
She hadn't been in town long,
但感觉参加派对已是如鱼得水
But, uh, she seemed like a real party girl.
你们俩当时在恋爱吗
Were the two of you dating?
没  我们只是朋友
Uh, no. Just friends.
-怎么  男女就不能只当朋友吗  -拜托
- What, can't a guy and a girl just be friends? - Please.
你们俩在一起了吗
Are you two together?
-还没  -绝对没有
- Not yet.  - Absolutely not.
和她的事没什么大不了
Look, it was, uh, no big deal.
我偶然提起我的一位校友
I happened to mention that a school friend of mine
要在皮尔逊俱乐部办个家族聚会
Was having a family reunion here at the Pierson Club
邀请我去参加
And asked me to stop by.
奥利维亚很想去  我就带上了她
Olivia really wanted to come. So I took her.
谁会想去参加别人的家族聚会
Who would want to go to someone else's family reunion?
我想这得看是哪个家族了
Well, I suppose that all depends on the family.
那次可是威尔士利家族的聚会
In this case, it happened to be the Wellesleys.
就是那个威尔士利家族
The w-- the "Wellesleys" Wellesleys?
那个财大势大的威尔士利家族
The rich and powerful Wellesleys?
保守党的那个  纽约威尔士利家族
The conservative, New York Wellesleys?
那不是某个参议员家族吗
Wasn't that one of our senators?
是的  卡斯帕·威尔士利参议员
Yeah, he was. Senator Casper Wellesley. Oh.
九十年代初期去世  他的孩子今年
He died in the early '90s. His kid's running for his seat
-再次参加了竞选  -我跟你说
- Again this year. - Well, I'll tell you what,
下次我接到邀请时  会带你一起去
Next time I'm invited, I'll take you.
迪伦翰先生  她被害当晚10点到凌晨2点
Mr. Dilahunt, where were you between 10:00 P.M. and 2:00 A.M.
你在哪里
The night that she was killed?
我和几个威尔士利家族的表亲
Okay, well, a couple of, uh, Wellesley cousins and I
从派对溜走去泡吧了
Bailed early and went clubbing.
我想当时我可能
I believe there may have been
喝多了点玻利维亚的什么烈酒
Bolivian marching powder involved.
我们因公共场合醉酒而被捕
We got picked up for public intoxication.
我父亲让他们放弃了起诉  不过
My father got the charges dropped, but, uh,
被捕记录还是没有撤销
There's still a record of our arrest.
你们要是找不到  我家还有装裱好的复印件
If you can't find it, I have a framed copy at home
当晚你和奥利维亚发生了争执吗
Did you have an argument with Olivia that night
-或见她和谁发生过争执  -都没有
- Or see anyone else who did?  - No.
有位女服务生看到奥利维亚跟一位
A witness saw Olivia having it out
穿蓝夹克  戴橙色条纹领带的男子发生争执
With a man in a blue blazer and an orange striped tie.
你想想  这个人会是谁
Do you remember anyone who fit that description?
事实上  我还真记得
Actually, I do.
威尔士利家族聚会都有严格的着装要求
All Wellesley family events have a strict dress code.
那个外衣是标准装
The, uh, blazers are standard,
但林内·威尔士利  家族族长
But Lenanne Wellesley, the family matriarch,
亲手挑选了男士的领带
Hand picks the men's ties.
你跟我想的一样吗
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
对  我们的嫌疑人多了去了
Yep. We got a hell of a lot of suspects.
是的  局长
Yes, chief.
我知道  局长
No, I know, chief.
我一定尽快  局长
As soon as I possibly can, chief.
他们要裁员20%
They cut our staff 20%,
局里破案率下降了3%  他们大为不爽
And they get upset when our closure rate drops 3%.
除非天降奇迹才可能有转机
You ask me, we're working miracles to do what we're doing.
有更紧要的话  我们稍后再谈
Sir, we can do this later if you have a higher priority.
永远别让工作妨碍了正事
Never let the job get in the way of the job.
有什么进展
Where were we?
布莱迪和他的联系人
Well, Brady and his contact communicated through
通过假邮箱帐号联系
A dummy email account.
我们想追踪邮件地址  但一无所获
We tried to trace the address, but it was a dead end.
狱警那边有什么进展
Where are we with reviewing the guards?
一无所获  监狱长拒绝提供值班表
No where. The warden refuses to provide the duty roster.
他说假设他的属下有问题
He said that he was offended
是我们对他的冒犯
We assume that one of his men was dirty.
他想要自己内部解决
He wants to handle it in house.
是吗  我可不接受
Yeah? Well, that doesn't work for me.
有没有谁像是在派对上
Do any of these men look like the one
同奥利维亚争吵的人
That you saw arguing with Olivia the night of the party?
十年前我只是个傻乎乎的服务生
Look, it was a stupid waitress job ten years ago.
你还记得十年前你在干什么吗
Do you remember what you were doing ten years ago?
你还记得一些细节吗
Can you recall any details?
他是否戴眼镜  有没有纹身
Was he wearing glasses? Did he have a tattoo?
我只知道当时  那个男人在吼那个女孩
All I know is that the man was yelling at the girl.
他非常恼怒  把酒都给洒了
He got so riled up, he spilled his wine.
最后是我清理了地毯上的污渍
And I ended up cleaning it off the carpet.
有洒到他自己身上吗
Did he spill any on himself?
我不知道  可能有
I don't know. Maybe.
他
Him!
特伦特·威尔士利吗
Trent Wellesley?
我是凯特·贝克特探长
I'm detective Kate Beckett
纽约警局的
NYPD.
我需要和你谈谈
I need to have a word.
是  我的老朋友杰夫说我可能受到询问
Yes. My old friend Jeff said I might be hearing from you.
警察  他们是警察吗
Police? Are they the police?
是的  祖母
Yes, grandmother.
我的戒指被偷了
My ring was stolen.
他们不是为你的事来的  祖母
Oh, oh, they're not here for you, grandmother.
我的戒指被偷了  那个很贵
My ring was stolen. It's expensive
特伦特  你们可能得到别的地方去说
Trent, perhaps you should take this conversation elsewhere
我明白  弗兰克  她有时候有点迷糊
Of course, Frank. She gets a little confused sometimes
好了
Okay.
我们快点把事情解决吧
Let's get this over with.
-是我  -你什么
- It was me.  - It was you, what?
那晚和杰夫带来的女孩
I was the one who had the argument with the girl that
争吵的就是我
Jeff brought to the reunion that night,
那个被杀的女孩
The girl  who was killed.
我对她的行为举止不满  就让她离开
I didn't care for her behavior, so I asked her to leave.
她那样的女孩混迹于
Girls like that hang around
像我这样的家庭是有目的的
Families like mine for a reason.
她们图谋不轨
They want something.
杰夫是把她作为女伴带过来的
Jeff brought her as his plus one.
不过那时候他已经离开了  而她却还在
But he had left by then, and she stayed.
她试图和我的几个家人搭讪
She tried to chat up more than one of my relatives.
有没有比较特别的
Any other in particular?
你找错人了
You're barking up the wrong tree.
我们家族的人和她的死没有任何关系
No one in my family had anything to do with what happened to her.
有人花了近一百万美元来掩盖真凶
Someone paid almost $1 million to cover up her murder.
因此你们家族每个人都有嫌疑  包括你
That makes everyone in your family a suspect, including you.
相信我  如果我有那么多钱来挥霍的话
Trust me, if I had that kind of money to throw around,
我也不会在这巴结老太太了
I wouldn't be here sucking up to the old lady.
不错的辩解
Nice.
你们认为我很有钱是因为我姓威尔士利
You think I'm rich because my last name is Wellesley
但在年幼时我父亲就过世了
But my dad died when I was a kid.
我和母亲很大程度上
Mom and me had to
是靠亲戚的救济生活
Pretty much survive off the handouts of relatives.
我想找个工作应该不难吧
Well, I suppose getting a job would be out of the question
你在保护谁
Who are you protecting?
你已经承认是和她争执过
You already admitted to arguing with her.
这样可不好
It really does not look good.
你们得明白
You have to understand...
他就像是我唯一的父亲
He's like the only father I have.
-你指谁  特伦特  -我叔叔温斯顿
- Who are you talking about, Trent?  - My uncle Winston.
他刚遭遇了痛苦的分手
He had just been through a bad break-up.
他是那种很容易被利用的人
He's the kind of person that people try to take advantage of?
比如谁
People like who,
奥利维亚或想从他那儿得到救济的穷亲戚
Olivia or poor relations looking for a handout?
我以前就看到过她和他在一起
I'd seen her with him before.
没错  那个女孩的遭遇的确很惨
Yes, it was terrible, what happened to that poor girl.
能告诉我们你和她
Could you tell us about the kind of relationship
是什么关系吗  威尔士利先生
You had with her, Mr. Wellesley?
在家庭聚会上那次是你们第一次见面吗
Was the reunion the first time that you two met?
事实上  我第一次见她
Actually, I believe I met Olivia
是在几周前的鸡尾酒会上
At a cocktail party a few weeks before that.
是在现代美术馆吗  我想不起来了
Was it MOMA? I don't recall.
反正  我很中意她
Anyway, I took a shine to her.
有魅力  有抱负
Charming, ambitious,
外表着装不怎样  但我可以指点一下她
Rough around the edges, but I felt I could mentor her.
"指点"是什么意思
And by "mentor" you mean?
你在暗示什么
What are you suggesting?
你侄子特伦特说
Your nephew Trent said
看到她整晚一直和你调情
That he saw her hitting on you the whole night.
那是特伦特的说法
Well, that's Trent for you.
他总是很小心地保护这个家族
He's always been very protective of the family.
她被害那晚
Where were you between 10:00 pm and 2:00 am
十点到凌晨两点你在哪里
On the night she was murdered?
你真的是在问我吗
Are you seriously asking me,
问温斯顿·威尔士利要不在场证明
Winston Wellesley, for an alibi?
看来是了
Oh. Apparently you are.
好吧  我在家
Fine. I was home.
有人能证明吗
Can anyone corroborate that?
-有啊  上帝  -威尔士利先生
- Yes. God.  - Mr. Wellesley,
你的车已经准备好了
Your car is ready.
和你们的谈话很愉快
As delightful as this conversation has been,
但我必须走了
I must take my leave.
我得去竞选总部见我弟弟
I have to meet my brother at his campaign headquarters.
没错  布莱克·威尔士利
Ah, yes, Blake Wellesley,
又一次竞选议员了
Running for senate again.
我们会很感激你们的支持
Mm-hmm. And we'd appreciate your support.
别忘了投票
Don't forget to vote.
我敢肯定他和奥利维亚有一腿
I have no doubt he was having an affair with Olivia.
但他为什么要杀她呢
But why would he kill her?
可能因为她和别人在一起而感到伤心
Do you think maybe he was upset that she came with someone else?
嫉妒  金钱  谋杀
Mm, jealousy, money, murder
有比这更好的情节吗
Does it get any better than this
你想挖出我侄女的尸体
You want to exhume my niece's body?
我们认为有关键证据
We believe that there was evidence
在验尸的时候被忽略了
Overlooked during the autopsy that could lead to her killer.
但你们告诉我已经抓到凶手了
Well, you told me you caught the man.
事情已经结束了
You told me it was over.
我以为是  但杀害奥利维亚的那个人
I thought it was, but whoever killed Olivia.
又杀了两个人
Just murdered two more people.
你的侄女应该得到公正  他们也是
Your niece deserves justice, and so do they.
她是一个那么特别的孩子
She was such a special girl.
当她妈妈的癌症恶化的时候
She quit school...
她为了照顾她而辍学
To take care of her mother when the cancer got bad.
这很有说服力
That says a lot about her.
她妈妈死后
After her mother passed,
她必须离开那个伤心之地
It was like she had to get away.
当她去了城市  我真替她高兴
When she moved to the city, I was just so happy for her.
你会  把她按原样重新下葬的吧
You'll... Bury her back the way she was?
当然
Of course.
至少还为她举办了像样的葬礼
At least she had the funeral she deserved.
多亏了威尔士利先生
Thank god for Mr. Wellesley.
威尔士利先生
Mr. Wellesley?
所有一切都是他付的钱
The man who paid for everything.
是哪个威尔士利先生
Which Mr. Wellesley was that?
温斯顿·威尔士利
Winston Wellesley
出钱为她举行葬礼
Paid for her funeral?
-是否是良心的谴责  -是
- Can anyone say "guilty conscience"?  - Yeah.
埃斯波西托
Hey, Esposito
调查一下温斯顿·威尔士利的不在场证明
Run down Winston Wellesley's alibi.
问问看门人  司机以及周围所有人
Talk to doormen, chauffeurs, the whole gamut.
我会尽力
I'll see what I can do.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是监狱值班表
The prison duty roster.
该怎么查呢  长官
How'd you pull it off, sir?
他们让我当领导
They didn't make me captain
不只因为我适合坐在办公桌后面
Just because I look good behind a desk.
差值班表上的所有警卫人员
Run all the guards on that roster.
看有无不同寻常之处
Look for anything out of the ordinary.
长官  我马上给公墓打电话
Sir, I'm gonna call the cemetery.
安排明天的开坟
To make arrangements to exhume the body tomorrow.
我搞不懂的是
You know what I don't get?
不管是谁在背后操作
Whoever is behind this
他为什么不再付钱给布莱迪
Why'd he stop paying Brady?
威尔士利家族多的是钱
These Wellesleys have plenty of money.
如果继续付钱的话  布莱迪绝不会
If the money hadn't stopped, Brady never would've set off
采取行动  进而引发这一切
This triggering domino that started all this.
我来给你解答  告诉你个秘密
Let me let you in on a little secret.
富人如何继续富有
You know how rich people stay rich?
他们很吝啬
They are cheap.
既然可以杀了布莱迪省钱
Why pay for Brady for the rest of his life
为何还要一辈子付钱给他
When you can kill him for a fraction of the price?
那他为何要等十年呢
But then why would he wait ten years?
事情有变  肯定发生了什么
Something changed. Something must have happened.
没错
Yeah.
蒙哥马利长官  我是布莱克·威尔士利
Captain Montgomery. Blake Wellesley.
很抱歉打扰你  能不能占用一点时间谈谈
Hate to bother you, but do you have a minute to chat?
我代表我们全家向你们保证
I speak for the entire Wellesley family
我们会全力配合你们调查这件案子
When I say you can expect our full cooperation in this investigation.
但是  你继续啊  "但是"来了
But? You can tell. There's a "but" coming.
不是"但是"  是"然而"
Not a "but" a "however"
正如我说的  我们会配合  然而
Like I said, we'll cooperate, however
我们希望不要再搞突然访问
We request that these unannounced interviews come to a stop
进入正题了
Here we go.
贝克特 让我们先听他说完
Beckett, let's hear him out.
我很抱歉这次
I apologize if I'm coming off
和他们一样突然造访  警官
Like one of those guys, detective.
只是突然造访有点让人难堪
It's just that these impromptu visits are a bit awkward.
我侄子特伦特
My nephew Trent
说你们找他谈话  当时他来看我母亲
Said you spoke to him when he visited my mother.
母亲变得很困惑  很伤心
Mother became very confused, very upset.
-我肯定有更好的办法  -比如
- I'm sure there's a better way to facilitate this.  - Like what?
我提议以后所有的访问
Well, I propose that all further interviews
都由我来配合  在我的办公室进行
Be coordinated by me and conducted at my offices.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
谢谢你的好意  威尔士利先生
Thank you for your offer, Mr. Wellesley.
-你真是太通情达理了  -不用客气
- That's very nice of you.  -Not at all.
我把我的电话号码给你
I'll give you my number.
等等  我也有 "然而"
Hold on. I, too, have a "however."
谢谢你的好意  然而
Thank you for your offer, however,
我的探员会以任何他们认为合适的方式
My detectives will conduct their investigation
进行调查
In any manner they see fit.
长官  我可以马上给你们局长打电话
Captain, I can get the commissioner on the phone in under a minute.
请便  替我向他问好
Well, tell him I said hi.
我愿意开专道迎接他
And I really could use a raise.
我们已无必要再谈
I think we're done here
真了不起
That was awesome.
不管你们在做什么  继续做
Whatever you guys are doing, keep doing it.
他们想耍花招
They're circling the wagons.
你太牛了
Awesome.
忽略  接受
"Ignore." "Accept."
忽略  不好
"Ignore." no.
接受  不好
"Accept." no.
母亲  别犹豫了
Oh, mother, come on.
接受他的邀请吧
Accept the man's friend request already.
用那张旧照片真是个很糟糕的主意
Using that old photo was a horrible idea.
你为什么不阻止我
Why didn't you stop me?
我何时有权阻止你做任何事情
Since when have I had the power to stop you from doing anything
如果查特期待的是八十年代的玛莎
What will Chet think if he expects 1980s-Martha,
结果看到的却是现在的我  他会怎么想
And... Pfft... Present-day Martha shows up?
若你告诉别人我的话  我绝对不承认
You tell anyone I said this and I'll deny it,
现在我只说一次
And I'm only gonna say it once.
八十年代的玛莎很美
1980s-Martha was pretty great.
但现在的玛莎照样很迷人
But present-day Martha...is pretty spectacular, too.
-你刚点"接受"了吗  -是啊
- Did you just accept that?  - Yeah
-那赶紧收回  -抱歉  不能收回
- Well, take it back.  - I'm sorry. I cannot
-我  天哪  -既然已经接受了
- I--oh, god.  - No, but since it's done,
为何不去浏览一下查特的主页
Why don't you take a visit to Chet's page
看看他现在是什么样子
And see what he looks like nowadays?
是这样吗  按那个
Uh, just like this? Press that?
天  那就是查特
Ooh, good l-- well, that's Chet.
但是  那是什么时候的照片
But... How old is that photo?
看来你们彼此彼此  妈妈
Turnabout is fair play, mother.
查特·帕拉本  你在想些什么
Chet Palaburn. What are you thinking, man?
一小时前工作人员把棺材送来了
City workers Brought the coffin in an hour ago.
好家伙  买这口棺材温斯顿可花费不少
Boy, Winston didn't spare any pennies with this box of wood.
-这是本特利灵柩  -你提前买好啦
- This is the Bentley of caskets.  - Shopping ahead?
调查过  德里克·斯道姆在《暴风预警》中
Research. Derrick Storm, in "Storm Warning,"
发现了杀人凶器
Finds a murder weapon.
在凶手现身的一年前就被藏在棺材内
Buried in a coffin a year before the murder occurs.
我在说给谁听呢  你知道这个
Who am I talking to? You know this.
回到非小说正题
Uh, back in the nonfiction section,
这里有一口埋藏了十年的真棺材
We have a real casket that's been sealed for ten years,
所以尸体可能已经严重腐烂
So there's gonna be some serious decomposition.
当我撬开它的时候
When I crack this open,
会有很强烈的尸臭味  做好准备
Expect the foulest of foul stenches.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Set?  - Ok.
尸体不见了吗
Is the body missing,
还是你刚表演了令人惊叹的魔术
Or did you just pull off an awesome magic trick?
你真了不起  长官
You are amazing, Sir.
没有  没发现指纹
Nope, no prints.
移走尸体的人很小心
Whoever removed Olivia's remains was careful.
这些人怎么会抢先我们一步
How do these people manage to stay one step ahead of us?
奥利维亚的姑姑说举行的是开放式葬礼
Olivia's aunt said it was an open-casket funeral.
那么她的尸体曾在这里
So her body must have been in here at one point.
殡葬公司肯定在葬礼和下葬的空隙
The mortuary company must have switched out the bodies
把尸体移走了
Between the funeral and the burial.
也许  但那个公司已经关门了
Yeah, but the company is out of bussiness
我们无从查找
So there's no way of finding out.
肯定是温斯顿出钱把尸体给处理了
Winston had to have paid to get rid of the body
以防布莱迪某天向警方澄清
Just in case Brady ever wanted to come clean with the police.
应该是这样
Mm-hmm. Looks like that.
这家伙准备了全套应急方案
This guy's got contingency plans for his contingency plans
我们像在和超级恶棍斗智斗勇
It feels like we're battling a super villain.
不好意思两位
Uh, excuse me, Dynamic Duo.
我该怎么处理这个呢
What am I doing with this?
得看情况了
Well, it depends
最近二手棺木行情如何
What can you get for a secondhand casket these days?
我给奥利维亚的家人打电话
I'll call Olivia's family
看他们打算怎么办
And find out what they want to do.
说真的
Seriously, though?
我在想一副九成新的棺材你可以卖多少
I wonder what you could get for a slightly used coffin.
那个可是最高档的
That thing is top of the line.
-你检查过抽屉吗  -什么抽屉
- Did you check the drawer?  - What drawer?
高档棺木通常
High-end coffins often have
在里面的某个地方藏有抽屉
A small drawer hidden somewhere in the lid.
以供家人放纪念品
That way families can place mementos in there
或变态凶手隐藏证据
Or psychotic killers can hide evidence.
谢谢  对不起
Thank you. Sorry.
没什么可疑的
Nothing suspicious.
只是些家庭照片
It's just a bunch of family photographs.
胸章上写了什么
What does that button say?
像是政治胸章
Looks like a political button.
埃德娜·德比西  是奥利维亚的母亲吗
"Edna Debiasse." Is Edna Debiasse Olivia's mother?
把你的放大镜借给我
Let me borrow your magnifying glass.
我没有放大镜
I don't have a magnifying glass.
那不是办案的必备装备吗
Isn't that standard issue for detectives?
从福尔摩斯开始就不是
No, not since Sherlock Holmes.
你可以用我的
You can use mine.
卡斯帕·威尔士利  78年参议院
"Casper WELLESLEY SENATE '78."
奥利维亚的妈妈为竞选工作
Olivia's mother worked on the campaign.
线索都指向威尔士利
All roads lead to Wellesley.
你在看色情电影吗
Are you looking at porn?
看色情电影我会用莱恩的电脑
I use Ryan's computer for that.
我在搜索一个期刊数据库
I've been searching a periodical database.
看我发现了什么  这篇文章
Look what I found. In this article,
关于1978年的参议院选举
It talks about how during his 1978 senate run,
卡斯帕的儿子  布莱克和温斯顿
Casper had his sons, Blake and Winston,
当时都在伊萨卡岛建立竞选总部
Heading up his campaign headquarters in Ithaca.
奥利维亚的母亲就在那里工作
Where Olivia's mom worked.
温斯顿一定认识她
She and Winston had to have crossed paths.
没错  那温斯顿为何隐瞒此事
Exactly. Now why would Winston keep that from us?
从布莱迪待的监狱里拿来的花名册
We ran all the guards' names off
每一个看守我们都查过
That duty roster you got us from Brady's prison.
他是唯一一个有问题的
He's the only one that red flagged.
名叫帕特森
Name's Patterson.
上个月他存入五千美元现金
Made a deposit last month for $5,000 cash.
布莱迪遇害当天
Then the day Brady was killed,
他又存了一次钱  一万块现金
He makes another deposit in cash, this time for $10,000.
我最恨就是制服蛀虫
If there's anything I hate, it's a dirtbag in uniform.
查实温斯顿·威尔士利的不在场证明了吗
So where are you guys at with Winston Wellesley's alibi?
有些线索了
We have a few leads.
继续找  我来处理这个
Keep pushing on that. I'll push on this.
威尔士利先生  我们想知道真相
Mr. Wellesley, we are going to find out the truth.
而我们能查出多少真相
And the amount of dust that we kick up doing
全取决于你的配合
That is entirely up to you.
我好像想起来了  我认识她
I do seem to recall, uh, making her acquaintance.
你又隐瞒了真相
You're telling us half-truths again.
我们已经知道你为奥利维亚付了丧葬费
We already know that you paid for Olivia's funeral.
还知道你认识她母亲
We know that you knew her mom.
要不你开始说实话
Either you start telling me the truth,
要不等我给媒体漏点口风
Or you're gonna spend the last few weeks
你弟弟竞选的最后几周
Of your brother's campaign issuing denials
你就忙着拒绝各大媒体的采访吧
After I release what I know to the press.
好  我认识她母亲
Fine. I knew her mother.
她母亲去世后
After her mother passed, Olivia set about
奥利维亚打算解开身世之谜
To unravel the mystery of her origins.
奥利维亚很聪明
Olivia was clever.
她根据手上的线索
She put together the clues,
发现她父亲是威尔士利家族的成员
Found out her father was a Wellesley--
威尔士利成员
A Wellesley
然后呢
And?
其实我就是奥利维亚的父亲
Actually, the truth is, I'm Olivia's father.
我知道很不可思议  十年前
I know. I had the same look on my face
她告诉我的时候  我的表情和你一样
When Olivia told me ten years ago.
奥利维亚的母亲没有告诉你吗
And Olivia's mother didn't tell you?
她也没有告诉奥利维亚
Mnh-mnh. Didn't tell Olivia either.
在我即将告诉大家真相时
I was just on the verge of telling everyone when she...
她却意外惨死了
When she was tragically killed.
亲父弑女  真是个悲剧
It is a tragedy when a father kills
不是吗
His daughter, isn't it?
什么
What?
奥利维亚的尸体失踪跟你有什么关系
What do you know about Olivia's missing body?
我不知道  太变态了
Nothing. That's obscene.
谁会做那种事
Who would do something like that?
你  这样就没人知道
You, so no one would ever find out the truth
她的真实身份了
Of who she really was.
我没杀她
I didn't kill her,
我也没有把她的尸体藏起来
And I certainly didn't hide her body.
还有  她已经去世十年
Yet, ten years after her death,
你却还在隐瞒她的存在
You're still trying to hide her existence.
你们得理解  我要保护我的家族
Well, you have to understand. I have a family to protect.
奥利维亚就是你的家人
Olivia was family.
温斯顿·威尔士利  你就是凶手
Winston Wellesley, you did it.
可能是他  但我们没有证据
He might have, but we don't have the evidence to prove it.
因为不是他干的
That's because he didn't.
我们找到了温斯顿的不在场证明
We were able to verify Winston's alibi.
他真的独自在家吗
He really was home alone?
他在家  但不是独自
Oh, he was home, but he wasn't alone.
温斯顿那晚有爱人相伴
Winston had some romantic company that night.
如果他有不在场证明
Well, then if he had an alibi,
为什么一开始他不说呢
Why didn't he just say so from the start?
也许因为他的情人是
Maybe because of who his romantic company was.
斯坦利·詹金斯
Stanley Jenkins.
斯坦利现在是男女通用的名字了吗
Is Stanley a unisex name now
还是说温斯顿
Or is Winston--
同性恋  没错  他是同性恋
Gay? Uh, yeah. He's gay.
他对我们撒谎  他在保护谁
He lied to us. Who is he protecting?
他已经告诉我们了
Well, he said it himself.
家族
Family.
你应该清楚这个年轻女子
You have to understand that this young woman--
奥利维亚  我不认识她
Olivia-- I hardly knew her.
也许在派对上我和她握过手
Maybe I shook her hand at the party,
但也仅此而已
But that's all.
现在你说她母亲三十年前和我
And now you're telling me her mother and I worked
同为竞选工作吗
The same campaign 30 years ago?
你和你哥哥78年7月和8月
You and your brother were in Ithaca
都在伊萨卡岛竞选总部
July and August of '78.
奥利维亚出生于79年5月
Olivia was born May, '79.
正是九个月之后
That's 9 months later.
你哥哥自己说是她父亲
Your brother claimed paternity,
但我们都知道那是不可能的
But I think we all know that's highly unlikely.
温斯顿  这到底是怎么回事
Winston, what the hell is going on here?
布莱克  是时候请律师了
Blake, it's time to get the lawyers involved.
这件事你知道什么  温斯顿
What did you know about this, Winston?
此时此地不适合说话
This is not the time or the place.
那年夏天之后我再没见过埃德娜
I never saw Edna after that summer.
她从来没告诉过我
She never told me anything.
那么你承认和她上过床吗
So you admit to sleeping with her?
她一定是不想惹麻烦
She must have not wanted to rock the boat,
不想让我父亲深陷丑闻
Hurt my father's campaign
影响我父亲的选举
With a scandal involving his son.
布莱克  你说的已经够多了
Blake, you've said enough.
我刚知道自己有个女儿
I just found out I had a daughter I never knew about,
一个十年前被谋杀
A daughter who was murdered
凶手却仍逍遥法外的女儿
And whose killer apparently is still at large.
你为什么跟警察说
Why did you tell the police
自己是她父亲  为什么
You were her father? Why?
事实上问题是
Actually the question is
他为何十年前这么告诉奥利维亚
Why did he tell Olivia that ten years ago?
你必须理解  布莱克
You have to understand, Blake.
这事发生在第一次参议员选举期间
This was during the first senate run.
这样的丑闻会让选举失利
Scandal would've killed the campaign.
但最后我还是输掉了选举
I lost the damn election anyway.
你无权不让我知道就做决定
You had no right to make that decision without me.
我们只是为了你着想
We were only looking out for your best interests.
我们  温斯顿  我们是指谁
We? Winston, who is "we"?
妈妈  你还记得奥利维亚
Mother, do you remember Olivia--
奥利维亚·德比西吗
Olivia Debiasse?
我当然记得  我记得很清楚
Of course I do. I have my mind.
威尔士利夫人  我们要
Mrs. Wellesley, we need to a--
你是谁
Who are you?
布莱克  她可不是奥利维亚
Blake, that's not Olivia.
妈妈  她是个警探
Yes, mother. This is a police Detective,
-正在调查  -好
- Investigating-- - Oh, yes.
我的戒指不见了
My ring was stolen.
它很贵的
It was very expensive.
好  夫人  但处理这件事之前
Yes, ma'am. Uh, but before we can deal with that,
我们要问您几个
We need to ask you a few questions
关于奥利维亚·德比西的问题
About Olivia Debiasse.
奥利维亚到我这里  说来找父亲
Olivia came to me looking for a father,
所以我告诉她是温斯顿
So I gave her Winston.
有个孩子能让他变得有点男人味
A child would go a long way to butch up his image.
但她是我的女儿  妈妈
But she was my daughter, mother.
你太出众了
You were too special.
你将会成为参议员
You're going to be a senator,
甚至可能当上总统
Maybe even president someday.
威尔士利夫人  奥利维亚被谋杀那天
Mrs. Wellesley, what happened to Olivia
究竟发生了什么
The night of her murder?
这么多问题都是关于...
Ooh! So many questions about--
我不关心这些问题
I don't care for questions.
奥利维亚也质问过我
Olivia questioned me.
粗鲁的女孩
Ugh! The gall of that girl.
威尔士利先生  你母亲有病
Mr. Wellesley, your mother is ill.
她不能承受压力
She can't handle the stress--
闭嘴  弗兰克  我什么都不怕
Oh, shut it, Frank. I can handle anything.
她焦虑的话会很危险
It's dangerous for her to get this riled up.
我到车上给她拿药
I'm getting her medication from the car.
为了找回我丢的戒指  还要做什么吗
What does any of this have to do with my stolen ring?
妈妈  你当晚去奥利维亚的公寓了吗
Mother... Did you go to Olivia's apartment that night?
她跟我作对  一定要阻止她
She crossed me, had to be stopped.
你做了什么  妈妈
What did you do, mother?
威尔士利夫人
Mrs. Wellesley...
是你杀死了奥利维亚·德比西吗
Did you kill Olivia Debiasse?
杀死她  我为什么要杀死她
Kill her? Why would I kill her?
没有
N-no.
我说"处理好这件事"
I... Said "take care of it,"
接着事情就安排妥当了
And it was taken care of.
你让谁去处理这件事
And who did you ask to take care of it?
是弗兰克·戴维斯吗
Well, well, well, if it isn't Frank Davis.
对不起  朋友  你认错人了
Sorry, pal. Got the wrong guy.
我可不这么想
I don't think so, pal.
我花了些时间
I just spent the better part of a day
审问一个叫帕特森的看守
Sweating a guard named Patterson,
他在布莱迪·汤姆逊遇害的监狱工作
Who works at the prison where Brady Thompson was killed.
我不认识什么布莱迪·汤姆逊
I don't know any Brady Thompson
也不认识帕特森
And I don't know any Patterson.
有意思  因为他认识你
That's funny, 'cause he knows you.
他说你贿赂他监听
Said that you paid him to monitor
布莱迪·汤姆逊寄包裹的电话
Brady Thompson's calls about a package.
不  别想跑
No. No, no, no.
说你付钱  让他找个被判无期的囚犯
Said that you paid him to have a lifer
把刀插进布莱迪·汤姆逊后背
Put a shiv in Brady Thompson's back.
现在你说我有没有抓错人
Now you tell me how I got the wrong guy.
手铐
Cuffs.
弗兰克是家族杀手吗
So Frank was the family hit man?
更像是位家族帮手
More like the family fixer.
他为威尔士利重新当选参议员
He cleaned up all types of dirt
扫清障碍
For senator Wellesley back in the day.
他知道下葬尸体的地方
He knows where all the bodies are buried.
也知道要挖出哪个
And which ones needed to be dug up.
按威尔士利夫人的命令
And then after he got rid of Olivia
摆脱奥利维亚后
On Mrs. Wellesley's orders,
他联系所有生活潦倒的朋友
He called around to all his low-life connections
直到找到愿意解决问题的家伙
Until he found someone desperate enough to cut a deal.
为什么十年后
Then why, after ten years,
不再为布莱迪蹲监狱付钱了
Would he suddenly stop paying Brady to do his jail time?
威尔士利夫人生病后
When Mrs. Wellesley lost her faculties,
布莱克负责管理家族事物
Blake was granted power of attorney.
弗兰克拿不到钱继续付款
Frank couldn't get the money to make the payments anymore.
所以他停止付款  打算让布莱迪消失
So he stopped, figuring Brady would just disappear?
当他发现布莱迪有证据
And when he found out Brady had evidence
证明自己无辜的时候  弗兰克慌了
To prove his innocence, Frank panicked.
他偷了威尔士利夫人的戒指抵押
He stole Mrs. Wellesley's ring and hocked it
换钱来让布莱迪彻底闭嘴
To finance his plan to shut Brady up permanently.
顺便说一下  看看分局完成的指标
By the way, took a look at the precinct's numbers.
破获三起案子
Three closed cases
让我们刚好达到要求的破案率
Puts us just over the mandated case closure rate,
正赶上应付明天的检查
Right in time for the review tomorrow.
你知道比那更好的是什么吗
You know what's even better than that?
十年后  我能打电话给奥利维亚的姑姑
After ten years, I can call Olivia's aunt
告诉她终于抓到了真凶
And tell her that we really got the guy, finally.
你也去告诉快递员的姐姐结果
And you get to give the messenger's sister some closure, too.
虽然我不知道  怎么说才能宽慰死者家属
Though I don't suppose having answers makes it any easier.
有办法  及时说就好
It does... In time.
难以置信
I can't believe
为了满足一个女人保护家族名誉的需要
How many lives were ruined over one woman's need
毁了多少生命
To protect her family's reputation.
你永远不会有这种烦恼的
You will never have this problem.
因为有你我和你奶奶
Between grams and myself,
我们的家族名誉已经毁了
Our family reputation's already in ruins.
我真幸运
Mm, lucky me.
布莱迪的儿子会怎么样呢
What's gonna happen to Brady's son?
乌云过后  阳光灿烂
Well, there's a silver lining there.
当布莱克·威尔士利知道
When Blake Wellesley found out
布莱迪为什么出卖自由
Why Brady sold his freedom...
他承诺向纽约儿童慈善团体捐款两千万
He pledged $20 million to a local kids' charity..
他们同意照顾布莱迪的儿子
Who agreed to handle Brady's son's care.
太好了
Oh, that's so sweet.
看起来真不错  奶奶  热辣约会吗
Lookin' good, Grams. Hot date?
和查特·帕拉本共进晚餐并还要共舞几曲
Dining and dancing with Chet Palaburn.
如果他变得又胖又丑怎么办
What if he turns out to be bloated and ugly?
你觉得我有多肤浅
Oh, how superficial do you think I am?
非常  妈妈  怎么了
Intensely. Mother, what is going on?
以前的玛莎回来了
Present-day Martha is going on.
我曾经富得流油
I've had filthy, stinking rich.
也曾经一无所有
I've had broke, dirt-poor.
知道现在我想要什么吗
And you know what I want now?
快乐  只是快乐
Fun. Just fun.
如果你不是查特期待的样子呢
And if you aren't what Chet's expecting?
拜托  亲爱的  看看我
Oh, please, darling. Look at me.
没有比这更棒的了
Come on. It doesn't get any better than that.
别等我了  孩子们
Don't wait up for me, kids.
妈妈出场了
Mama's on the prowl.
这老不羞
Oh, that poor bastard.
这种疯狂会遗传吗
Is insanity inherited?
欢迎有能力的影视爱好者加入我们字幕组
加入仅凭个人兴趣爱好 没有任何金钱实质回报